Ismaila Afuwape

Etobicoke, Ontario M9V 5G7 • 647-707-9952 • ismaila.afuwape@gmail.com*

My Website Portfolio: https://afuwapemoyo.github.io/ismailaafuwape.github.io/

www.linkedin.com/in/ismaila-afuwape

Status: Canadian Permanent Resident

Education: B.Sc., B. Ed Economics/Education, Postgraduate Info Tech Solution.

PROFILE

A motivated and proactive individual with a wide range of IT knowledge and expertise gathered over the span of 7+ years in healthcare and financial projects. Able to learn unfamiliar material and techniques quickly, exhibit great attention to detail, execute under aggressive deadlines, and adapt quickly to changing circumstances and systems to maintain strategic vision of the organization and link it with everyday work. Very passionate about projects and able to carry out tasks that are time sensitive in an efficient manner to guarantee the growth and success of the organization. A wonderful team player who values collaboration and communication, eager and possesses a very strong work ethic and can relate and work efficiently with diverse groups

HIGHLIGHTS OF QUALIFICATIONS –

- Recent graduate of the Information technology solution Postgraduate program at Humber College (May 2021)
- Bachelor's Degree in economics
- Agile methodology
- Effective communication skills
- Organized, time management and project management skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Troubleshooting: Ability to troubleshoot hardware, software, and peripheral devices including:

printers, network issues, operating systems

Programming Languages: HTML & CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, SOL, PL/SOL, R,

React JS, Node JS, Hadoop / Hive, Java, Python, C#, and documentation

Software: NetBeans, Visual Studio, MS Office 365, Eclipse, Data Modeler, Neo4j Desktop,

SQL Server Management Studio, SQL Developer, R Studio, PyCharm, Visual Paradigm.

Operating Systems: Windows 7/8/XP/10, Linux, Ubuntu CentOS, Mac iOS

Database: Oracle 9i, 10g, 11g, MS SQL Server, JDBC, Mango DB, MySQL

Web Technology: HTML5, Java Script, XML, PHP, Context API

ETL/Other Tools: Informatica Power Center 8.6.1/9, SAS Base 9.x, SAS Enterprise Guide, SSIS

(Visual Studio), Erwin Data Modeler, ER Assistant

Business Intelligence Tools: Tableau 9.1, 9.2, 9.3, 10.4, PowerBI, Excel and PowerPivot, Microstrategy, SSRS

Relevant Courses:

Oracle Database
 Amazon Ec2 Instance
 Html 5 / CSS

Php
 XML
 Big Data, R programming

SQL tunning/ SQL Server
 JavaScript
 Apex

I. Afuwape Page 2 of 2

Relevant Competencies

- Creating reports and ETL process with SSIS, SSRS. Experience in data scrubbing and cleansing.
- Hands on Big Data tools like HDFS, Spark, MapReduce, HBASE, Pig.
- Developed an intermediate knowledge of relational database concepts and how to interact with databases using SQL, procedure, trigger.
- Great understanding of SDLC methodologies such as Waterfall and SCRUM specifically Agile).
- Use SAS to import and export data from and into SAS tables. Excellent knowledge of SQL
- Knowledge of healthcare information systems, experience with Practice Management software and HIPAA Guidelines.
- Hands on experience in SAS programming for extracting data from Flat files, Excel spreadsheets and external RDBMS (SQL SERVER/ ORACLE) tables using LIBNAME and SQL PASSTHRU facility.
- Using tools like Microsoft SQL server management studio to connect and query SQL server
- Data visualisation and Experience working with different dataset, JSON, XML, CSV/Excel, FLAT file.
- Experienced in Data extraction from a given sources, Data uploading into a staging area, Data formatting to meet the defined standards, Data cleansing, Data structuring/mapping, Loading structured data into the warehouse.
- Hands on with Microsoft SQL Server Report Builder to add a key performance indicator (KPI) to a Reporting Services paginated report.
- Capable of performing tuning to improve performance and installing reporting tools.
- Experience working with large data and trace log files using Microsoft SQL server Data tools (SSDT) for Visual studio.

EDUCATION

Data Analytics, Certificate September 2021

George Brown College, Toronto, ON Skills for change 8 weeks Bridge2Work Program

Information Technology Solutions, Postgraduate April 2021

Humber College, Toronto, ON

Academic Upgrading, ACE Certificate of Completion July 2019

Humber College, Toronto, ON

Computer Programming/Network Training Institute Feb 2007

Ogun State Southwest Resource Centre Academy

Bachelor of Economics/Education April 2005

Olabisi Onabanjo University, Ago-Iwoye, Nigeria

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Momentuum BPO Inc, Toronto, ON Student Internship

Jan 2021 – April 2021

- Implemented e-signature to an existing project.
- Design Front End UI report page connecting to SQL server database to retrieve specific data
- Write weekly report about progress of project
- Give feedback of about project through Jira and Push codes to Bitbucket repo.
- Implemented DocuSign to exiting web form project. (Classic ASP, ASP.NET, C#, HTML, CSS, JS, SQL)

I. Afuwape Page 3 of 3

WORK EXPERIENCE Cont...:

Magic K Touch Serviced Ltd, Abeokuta, Nigeria Database Programmer

Feb 2008 - March 2016

- Strong in ETL data validation developed using Informatica/SSIS ETL environments
- Develop and Design ETL test cases, scenarios, and scripts to ensure quality Data warehouse / BI applications
- Used advanced SQL concepts like OLAP, Group By and aggregate functions
- Used complex SQL queries in advance to fetch data from other tools.
- Worked with ETL Process which includes SSAS, SSIS, and SSRS.
- Worked with Business Intelligent tools like Tableau and Power BI on SQL server
- mainframe.
- Developed stored procedures, views, triggers for analysis.
- Involved in creating database objects like tables, views, procedures, triggers, and
- functions using T-SQL to provide definition, structure and to maintain data efficiently.
- Developed Tableau visualizations and dashboards using Tableau Desktop.

ACIC Ltd, Abeokuta, Nigeria Data Analyst

Feb 2007 – Feb 2008

- Wrote complex SQL queries using advanced SQL concepts like Aggregate functions.
- Performed ad-hoc reporting analysis as well as manipulate complex data on MS SQL server.
- Perform data information collection from internal and external sources, verification, and entry into the database. Work with vendors for evaluation of data reporting enhancement
- Analyzed duplicate data or errors in data to provide appropriate inter-departmental
- communication and monthly reports.
- Adhere to data security and relevant legislation
- Provided outstanding and professional customer support: achieved a record 100% customer satisfaction rating

References Available Upon Request